D/L David Linares

- (902) 541 74 29
- aceituno864@gmail.com
- Pridgewater / NS / Canada
- in/david-aceituno-478128204/
- https://davidaceituno88.
 github.io/DavidAnalyst.
 github.io/

ABOUT ME

Data Analyst living in Canada, skilled in SQL, EXCEL AND POWER BI, with professional and personal projects experience. MMA Coach and 10^{TH} Planet Jiujitsu practitioner under Eddie Bravo.

You can visit my portfolio website here and my GitHub here

SKILLS

SQL	
POWER BI	
Excel	
MS OFFICE	

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree Computer Science *UABC, Mexico* 2006 – 2011

The Complete Oracle SQL Certification Course

UDEMY

Feb 2022

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-89a1e7ao-9ccb-4953-abd9-ac9a11899bf4/

EXPERIENCE

TRADES SCHOOL Data Analyst

CECATI 83 / Municipal Trades School in my hometown / Mexico Jan 2021 – Jan 2022

Analyze data related to their students and potential new students so that they could come up with better marketing strategies

- Created a dashboard with **Power Bi** to help the trades school create better strategies to attract more students and help solve the skilled labor shortage.
- Transformed and processed the .csv file with **SQL** provided by the school, so that it will be more readable, and less redundant.
- Created measures, to help the manipulation and calculations of the data.
- Worked side by side with the school Directives so that they could get the best dashboard I could provide to them.

Marketing Associate

First Point Solutions / Marketing company / Mexico Jan 2022 – Apr 2022

In charge to build databases of potential clients

- Utilized CRM software to help the marketing team create marketing strategies and target more desirable clients
- Utilized Excel to create datasets of clients.
- Created a web scraper for some websites that contained potential client's information.

Canada's Unemployment Analysis and Forecast -

Personal Project – Bridgewater, Nova Scotia July 2023

My Background:

When I finished my Bachelor's in Computer Science, I owned a small web development start up. But after a while I got the opportunity to own a Mixed Martial Arts and Fitness gym, and I decided to go into an adventure that lasted more than 6 Years, that opportunity grew into one of the best Bootcamp Gyms in Ensenada and in many amateur and Professional MMA and BJJ champions. I also traveled very often to LA so that I could train under Eddie Bravo and become a 10th planet Jiu-jitsu student, because of that I was able to share the mats with legends of this discipline such as Joe Rogan, Kelvin Gastelum, Tony Ferguson and many more.

After COVID I decided to improve the quality of life that I wanted to give to my family so I decided to leave everything behind and migrate to this beautiful country where I could exploit all of my skills and talents to the maximum. With the confidence that my mindset and disciplined that I've obtained over the years through martial arts and taking on big challenges such as owning my own business, will allow me to conquer any new challenges and add value to any company that hires me.

Data analysis on the historic Employment and Unemployment rate of Canada.

This Analysis aims to give a better perspective on where does Canada stands now regarding the Unemployment and Employment Rate compared to previous years. In order to make this analysis possible, I got a data set that contains all the unemployment and employment rates since 1976, including the number of part time and full-time jobs, minimum age and maximum age of employees, etc.

- ETL the data from a data set using SQL
- Codded a Python web scrapper to get all the information of the prime ministers of Canada.
- Created a Power BI dashboard to visualize the new demographic distribution and how it changed over the years, using Maps, charts, gauge meter, DAX functions, etc.

USA NHTSA Road Safety Analysis --

Personal Project – Bridgewater, Nova Scotia June 2023

This Data Analysis aims to provide with a clearer view about the historical records on the Road Safety in the USA We can visualize the historical records by state regarding, Number of deaths, Fatality Rate, Miles Driven, etc.

Python Web Scraper --

Personal Project – Bridgewater, Nova Scotia

June 2023

Developed a web scraper tool while working as part of the marketing team for the Company *First Point Solutions*; this toll went into Tech Conferences websites, and get the information of the speakers attending the conferences, so that later we can create a contact list and reach out to them.

General **L**abor -- Drywall

JND Construction / Linares Taping – Bridgewater, Nova Scotia Apr 2022 - Present

- Use power tools for, renovations and help build new homes.
- Use pneumatic tools to build, roof structures and wooden walls
- Use automatic taping tools
- Install gypsum board

Gym Owner --

Team Delante MMA and Fitness Aug 2014 - Apr 2021

Owned a very successful Mixed Martial Arts and Bootcamp Training gym for more than 6 years . Had the chance to help hundreds of clients to improve their health, confidence and fitness levels. Coached professional MMA Fighters, Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu practitioners and competitors, which allowed my team to travel across Mexico and the USA. Got my belt under Eddie Bravo due to having a **10**th **PLANET Jiu-Jitsu** membership. Had the chance to train next to Joe Rogan, Kevin Gastelum, Tony Ferguson, and many other legends of the Martial Arts world.